Nick Lennon

Junior Full Stack Web Developer

nicklennondev@gmail.com • London/Surrey

https://github.com/nlenno1 • https://www.linkedin.com/in/n-lennon/ • https://nlenno1.github.io/dev-portfolio-site/

Executive Summary

Junior Software Developer with a Diploma in Full stack Software Development from the Code Institute. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Python. I have 10 years experience in the Music Industry and therefore I am a highly motivated valuable teamplayer with strong communication skills, and with an effective problem solving ability. I am eager to gain entry into the tech industry where I can learn, grow and contribute!

Education

February 2020 – April 2021 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development - Distinction

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland - University Accredited by Edinburgh Napier University Involves working on a learning program designed to replicate a modern Saas Environment while regularly using Slack,

Google Suite and Zoom

September 2012 – June 2014 Bachelor of Arts (Hons), Contemporary Music Performance

The Academy Of Contemporary Music, Guildford, UK

Technical Skillset

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python
Databases: MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres

Frameworks/Libraries: Django, Flask, jQuery, Jinja, Bootstrap

Version Control: Git, Github, VS Code

Portfolio projects

1. **Electrillo** - Website developed as part of Code Institutes Earth Day Hackathon (April 2022) and achieved 1st Place. This project helps the User understand and calculate the savings they could make by changing to an electric car and provides them with suggestions on what make and model would fit their requirements best.

Technologies Used - HTML5 , CSS with Bootstrap 5, JavaScript and a local JSON file as a database. **GitHub** - https://github.com/alissatroiano/team-4-april-2022

- **2. GymFit** E-commerce and Exercise Class Booking site for a local Fitness Center to advertise classes that sare offered, allow users to book onto and pay for classes or buy access packages to use.
 - **Technologies Used** HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap 5, JavaScript, Python, Django framework, Postgres DB, Stripe API for payments and AWS for hosting media. **GitHub** https://github.com/nlenno1/gym-fit-ms4
- 3. MovieWiki A movie review site that allows users to add movies to the database and control their dataset of reveiws on any movie. Technologies Used HTML5 , CSS with Bootstrap 5, JavaScript, MongoDB. GitHub https://github.com/nlenno1/moviewiki-ms3
- 4. FindMyMeal A search website ingratiating the Spoonacular API to allow users to find appropriate recipes for their circumstance. Technologies Used HTML5 , CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript, Spoonacular API. GitHub https://github.com/nlenno1/find-my-meal-ms2

Collaborative projects

Electrillo - Website developed as part of Code Institutes Earth Day Hackathon (April 2022) and achieved 1st Place. This project helps the User understand and calculate the savings they could make by changing to an electric car and provides them with suggestions on what make and model would fit their requirements best.

Technologies Used - HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap 5, JavaScript and a local JSON file as a database.

GitHub - https://github.com/alissatroiano/team-4-april-2022

Work Experience

November 2014 - Present

Profession Drummer and Percussionist, Self Employed

Global

- Working in all areas of the industry including Theatre Shows, Events, Weddings, Orchestras, Varied Size Group Performances, Recording and Cruise Ships.
- Worked in a array of positions on board cruise ships as a Drummer and Musical Director for the companies Cunard, P&O, P&O Australia and SAGA from June 2016 until February 2020.
- Responsibilities included communication with clients and employers to secure jobs which advanced my **Public Relations**, accounting for all income and expenses, managing time to allow for adequate preparation and travel time for jobs, gear maintenance and the performances themselves.
- Developed Self Motivation, Initiative, Problem Solving and Time Management skills due to the challenges of being self employed. Improved Team Work and Leadership skills from working with different artists and groups, which contain people with different skill sets, and working as a musical director to manage them and achieve the best results from the task.

November 2014 - June 2016

February 2020 - Present

Drum Kit and Percussion Tutor, Self Employed & Multiple Companies

London & North Surrey, GB

- Worked for establishments such as Realistic Music Academy (Epsom), Surbiton RBL Youth Marching Band, Kingston Music Services, The British School of Rock (Weybridge), The Rock Project.
- Responsibilities included weekly lesson planning, pupil progress tracking to ensure progress goals are met and liaising
 with other tutors/section heads as well as instructing in the sessions.
- Developed Leadership and Tutoring Skills as part of teaching individual students as well as group/ensemble tuition in
 mixed ability settings and advanced my use of SAAS video calling systems to facilitate Remote lessons when required.

October 2020 - September 2021 Customer Assistant, Lidl GB

Dorking, Surrey

- Worked as a Customer Assistant who specialised in Limited Offer Stock Rotation and Bakery Operation
- Responsibilities included Customer Service, Checkout Operation, Stock Checks and Rotations, Product Merchandising (including Limited Offer items), Bakery Operation (including Hygiene and Practice Checks) and Training of new staff members.
- Developed my Proactivity to solve issues before/as they arise, gained experienced working as a member of a Team in
 a Corporate structure while Taking Direction and Instruction from Management, improved Public Relations including
 learning the companies Conflict Resolution Processes and enhanced my Initiative and Problem Solving abilities
 especially when working with stock rotations.

Certifications

- Teeside University Summer University Course in Programming (August 2020)
- Teeside University Summer University Course in Cyber Security (August 2020)

Interests/Additional Information

- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Earth Day '22 We placed 1st in this collaborative project
- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Hacktober Fest A Halloween themed collaborative event
- Drummer and Percussionist who performs regularly
- Fluent English
- Running, Hiking and Gym fitness
- Full Drivers License